

I am an experienced software engineer and programming enthusiast with a wealth of experience in developing both low- and high-level software applications. Currently, I specialize in Go, containerized microservices, scalable architectures, event-driven systems, DDD, and cloud technologies. Recently, I have begun exploring the practical business applications of modern AI solutions.

EXPERIENCES

Software Engineer

May 2018 - Present

Self-Employed [B2B]

I have been working as a contractor on multiple projects in roles such as Senior or Tech Lead Software Engineer, undertaking the following responsibilities:

- Designing and developing modern applications based on containerized, event-driven microservices, prepared for cloud scalability.
- Leading software development initiatives with a focus on Clean Architecture, DDD, and Agile methodologies.
- Close collaboration with product stakeholders to design effective solutions.
- Contributing to open-source projects.

Technologies: Go, Kubernetes, Docker, GCP, Firestore, PostgreSQL, Microservices, Event-Driven, Cloud

Software Developer Lead

January 2016 - May 2018

UBS

Responsible for architectural design, implementation, testing, maintenance, and deployment of internal enterprise applications. Technical leader of the development team and scrum master.

Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, JS, AngularJS, Apache Solr, Oracle DB, Jenkins, Tomcat

Software Developer

Comarch

December 2014 - January 2016

Responsible for implementation, testing, and deployment of the new features for the cloud-based backup and file synchronization service.

Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, C#, .NET 3.5+, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Lead Industrial Automation Software Engineer

June 2013 - December 2014

teamtechnik Group

Responsible for implementation, testing, deployment, and commissioning of full stack software applications (low-level automation as well as auxiliary high-level applications) of assembly and testing lines for the automotive industry. Responsible for the technical leading of project-oriented international teams.

Accomplished several projects in Poland, China, and Germany.

Technologies: C#, .NET 3.5+, Oracle DB, Siemens Simatic S7

Industrial Automation Software Engineer

April 2013 - June 2013

teamtechnik Group

Responsible for implementation, testing, and commissioning of low-level automation systems of assembly and testing lines for the automotive industry.

Industrial Automation Software Engineer

March 2012 – April 2013

Siemens

Responsible for implementation, testing, and commissioning of low-level automation systems of hot steel rolling mills.

Accomplished several projects in Poland, Germany, and Turkey.

PROJECTS

.truespace - A platform offering users access to sophisticated internet profiling and modern AI capabilities for personal growth.

GetHarley - The first telehealth platform connecting individuals to experienced clinicians for a personalised discovery of products and treatments.

KARHOO - A leading technology platform that enables commercial partners to offer ground transportation services worldwide.

go-structurizr - An open-source library for auto-generating C4 diagrams from Golang applications.

Sabre NGP - A modern cloud-based application infrastructure focused on a high performance and development experience.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCY





Experienced Software Engineer

reczek.krzysztof@gmail.com

Cracow, Poland

krzysztofreczek

Resume PDF

EDUCATION

Mechatronics, Automation, and Robotics. Master's Degree.

AGH University of Science and Technology October 2006 - June 2011

LANGUAGES

Polish (Native)

English (Professional)

INTERESTS

Skateboarding, Cycling & Hiking

Music Production